

ADDRESS: 192 Spencer Street 4B, Brooklyn, NY 11201

EMAIL: eric.fino@gmail.com

PHONE: 203.435.1340

PROFILE I am a talented and hard working artist driven by a desire to create new and exciting things. Throughout my career in technology, I've had the fortune of working on some amazing projects. From experimental video mashup tools to Nike product customization software, I've made things that both inspire creativity and increase business profits. As a developer, my skills range from Adaptive-Responsive Design with HTML and CSS to scripting languages like Javascript and ActionScript, as well as some server-side languages like PHP. As a team leader, my broad range of experiences in video production, visual design and user experience help me to facilitate highly cohesive interactions across departments, resulting in very high-quality, successful work.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Team Leader: R/GA, New York, NY (08/2012 - Present)

Managed a team of up to 10 people - including front-end developers, UX and visual designers, and a quality assurance engineer - for the redesign of the Converse e-commerce website. One significant feature has been the shoe customizer, which allows users to design their own shoe on both desktop and mobile devices. The resulting prototype from this scope of work has since been used throughout the company as a standard for adaptive-responsive design.

Senior Open Standards Developer: R/GA, New York, NY (08/2011 - 08/2012)

Have worked on projects that range from an adaptive-responsive video web app for an in-store retail installation, to e-commerce websites with innovative features such as an inline PDP/"Quick-buy" solution.

Flash Developer: R/GA, New York, NY (04/2010 - 08/2011)

Worked on all-Flash e-commerce websites for high-profile clients such as Converse and Nike, adding enhancement features and making performance optimizations. Have been a developer on highly innovative projects such as the Nike Team Sports uniform builder. This project uses Embodee technology to dynamically map fabrics to 3D human models, and allows users to interactively customize various pieces of a uniform. Have also spear-headed the use prototypes for pitch work, with an experiment that uploads images to generate a color palette and auto-customize a sneaker.

Senior Flash Engineer: Mediatronica, Inc., New York, NY (10/2006 – 04/2010)

Built customizable, XML driven user interface systems that generate sharable Flash widgets with features revolved around, gaming, social behavior, web cameras, video, audio, and multi-user functionality. One notable application was the video remix/mashup tool. Working with local artists such as Eclectic Method and Reggie Watts to generate content, this application lets the user hit keyboard keys to rhythmically trigger video clips, set to a background beat. The first iteration of this, branded for the release of Innerpartysystem's "Don't Stop" music video, was nominated for a Webby in 2009.

Freelance Flash Developer: New York, NY (05/2006 - 03/2009)

Developed educational children's games for sites which include ShelSilverstein and MouseCookieBooks.com. Commissioned to develop the software portion of a physical game installation that teaches kids how the stock market works, which is now on permanent exhibit at the Children's Museum of Houston. Have developed various interactive maps, utilizing APIs such as Google Maps and Papervision3D.

Teacher's Assistant: Advanced Education System, New York, NY (02/2006 - 08/2006) Assisted in lectures and one-on-one training for a pilot program aimed at inspiring High School teachers to learn technology, and incorporate it into their standard curriculum.

Web Developer/Graphic Design/Print Production: Vertrue, Inc, Stamford, CT (8/2003 - 1/2004) Created original logo designs for web sites, and also built animated ad banners in both HTML and AS1.

EDUCATION

MPS Interactive Telecommunications Program

New York University Graduated Tisch School of the Arts 09/2004 - 05/2006 New York, NY 10003

BFA Graphic Design

University of Massachusetts Lowell Graduated 09/1999 - 12/2003 Lowell, MA 01852

SKILLS Management Skills

Scrum master

Source management: SVN, Git and Mercurial

Agile methodologies

Client relationships

Bug tracking: Fogbugz and JIRA On-boarding & documentation

Developer skills

Languages, Libraries and APIs

HTML CSS

Sass Javascript JQuery JQuery UI XML ActionScript 3

Server-Side ActionScript

Papervision3D Greensock Google Maps API YouTube API

Other languages

PHP MySQL Processing Arduino Android C++

IDEs and Other tools

Sublime Text Eclipse Dreamweaver Charles Web Proxy Flash Flash Builder

Other Skills

Photoshop Illustrator Final Cut Pro Premier Blender

Adobe Media Encoder

References available upon request.